The glory, the suspense, the spectacular drama of the men who won
the most decisive naval battle in our history!
Midway is a action, drama, history film directed by Jack Smight.
This war drama depicts the U.S.
and Japanese forces in the naval Battle of Midway, which became a
turning point for Americans during World War II.
Capt. Matthew Garth, played by Charlton Heston.
Adm. Chester W. Nimitz, played by Henry Fonda.
Capt. Vinton Maddox, played by James Coburn.
Rear Admiral Raymond A. Spruance, played by Glenn Ford.
Cmdr. Joseph Rochefort, played by Hal Holbrook.
Vice Adm. William F. 'Bull' Halsey Jr., played by Robert Mitchum.
Midway, released in the United Kingdom as Battle of Midway, is a 1976 American war film that
chronicles the Battle of Midway, a turning point in the Pacific War of World War II.
Directed by Jack Smight and produced by Walter
Mirisch from a screenplay by Donald S.
Sanford, the film starred Charlton Heston and Henry Fonda, supported by a large international cast of guest stars including James Coburn, Glenn Ford, Ed Nelson, Hal
Holbrook, Robert Webber, Toshiro Mifune, Robert Mitchum, Cliff Robertson, Robert Wagner, Pat Morita, Dabney Coleman, Erik Estrada and Tom Selleck.
The film was made using Technicolor, and its soundtrack used Sensurround to augment the
physical sensation of engine noise, explosions, crashes and gunfire.
Despite mixed reviews, particularly involving the use of stock footage and an unnecessary romance
subplot, the music score by John Williams and the cinematography by Harry Stradling Jr.
were highly regarded; as evidenced when Midway became the tenth
most popular movie at the box office in 1976.
The film explores themes of world war ii, u.s. navy, based on
true story, battle of midway, pacific war.
The tone is emotional and intense.